hollywoodbowl.com 2019-06-03

# Privacy Policy | Hollywood Bowl

The Los Angeles Philharmonic Association (the "ASSOCIATION") knows that you care how personal information you provide to us is used and shared. The ASSOCIATION adopted this Privacy Statement to inform users of how the Association's websites and mobile application collect, store, and use personal information submitted via the sites and mobile application owned and operated by the ASSOCIATION. By interacting with the ASSOCIATION websites and/or mobile application, you agree to and accept the practices described in this privacy notice.

I. INFORMATION COLLECTED

A. INFORMATION YOU GIVE US.  Certain applications on the ASSOCIATION websites and mobile application may require users to register or to provide personal information in order to make a purchase, or to be included on our electronic mailing lists. To better understand the needs of our website and mobile application users, we may also request information on users from time to time on a voluntary basis. Such information gathered and provided to any third party does not contain any information that identifies the user, but contains generalized, aggregate data or so called "demographic information." Entry of such information is optional and if you choose not to enter such information, you can successfully use these applications.  If you share demographic information with third parties, we will only provide aggregate data.

B. AUTOMATIC INFORMATION. Certain applications in the ASSOCIATION websites and mobile application invoke a standard feature found in web browser software called "cookies." "Cookies" are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer's hard drive through your web browser to enable our systems to recognize your browser, track the progress of e-commerce transactions, and to allow you to move from one page to the next without having to re-enter personal order information. We do not use or share information transferred through cookies with third parties for marketing or other purposes. Although most web browsers automatically accept cookies, you can change the configuration of your browser to prevent this from occurring. Of course, we recommend that you leave cookies "turned on" so that we can offer you more personalized service. In addition to information we gather by the use of cookies, we also automatically receive and store certain other types of information whenever you interact with us. For example, our servers track the type of web browser you are using, and the page to which you link from the ASSOCIATION websites or mobile application. We collect this information to better understand what products and services are of interest to visitors to the ASSOCIATION websites and mobile application.

II. USE OF INFORMATION COLLECTED

A. ELECTRONIC MAIL. If you have opted-into receiving electronic mail communication from the ASSOCIATION, we may use your personal information to email you regarding special offers from the ASSOCIATION, updated information about the ASSOCIATION or the ASSOCIATION websites, or ways in which we can improve your experience at that site. All such emails sent to you by the ASSOCIATION will allow you to opt-out of future electronic communications from the Association.

B. OTHER CONTACTS. If you provide your email address or have opted-in to receiving electronic mail communications, the ASSOCIATION may also use your personal information to contact you by mail, by email, or by telephone regarding special offers from the ASSOCIATION, updated information about the ASSOCIATION or the ASSOCIATION websites, and new services offered by the ASSOCIATION. If you wish to be removed from this contact list, you may do so by contacting the ASSOCIATION directly. (See the ‘Contact Us’ section below).

III. CONTESTS

The ASSOCIATION may occasionally present a special contest or promotion on its websites and/or mobile application that is sponsored by another company. To qualify for entry, we may ask you to provide personal information. If we plan to share that information with the sponsor(s), we will provide a statement to that effect.

IV. PROTECTION OF THE ASSOCIATION AND OTHERS

We release account and other personal information when required and in compliance with any law, or protect the rights, property, or safety of the ASSOCIATION, our users, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

In order to purchase tickets or merchandise, exchange tickets or access subscriber services, join our Email Clubs, and participate in contests and/or surveys, you must complete a registration form. Our site's registration form requires you to provide and verify basic contact information (such as your name and email address).

This information is used to contact you about services in which you have expressed interest. It is optional for you to provide additional demographic information (such as income level and gender), but it is encouraged so we may provide a more personalized and meaningful experience on our site.

V. SECURITY

The sites have security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. Our secure server software (SSL) is the industry standard and among the best software available today for secure commerce transactions. It encrypts all of your personal information, including credit card number, name, and address, so that it cannot be read as the information travels over the internet.

VI. LINKS

The ASSOCIATION is committed to protecting your privacy; however, this privacy notice applies only to the information collected via the ASSOCIATION websites and mobile application.

VII. CONTACT US/HOW TO UPDATE YOUR PERSONAL  INFORMATION

You can help the ASSOCIATION maintain the accuracy of your personal information by notifying us when you change your address, phone number, or email address. Contact us via the information on the websites' Contact Us pages if you wish to update your information or if you no longer wish to receive communications from the ASSOCIATION. You can also write to us at: The Los Angeles Philharmonic Association, 151 S. Grand Avenue, Los Angeles, CA, 90012.

Please address comments or questions regarding the ASSOCIATION’s privacy practices to us at the address listed above.

VIII. CONDITIONS OF USE, NOTICES, AND REVISIONS

If you choose to interact with the ASSOCIATION websites and/or mobile application, your visit and any dispute over privacy is subject to this privacy notice. This notice may change, and use of information that we gather now is subject to the privacy notice in effect at the time of use. You should check the ASSOCIATION websites and/or mobile application periodically to see recent changes.

If we decide to change our Privacy Statement, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We will use information in accordance with the Privacy Statement under which the information was collected.

If, however, we are going to use users' personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection, we will notify users via email. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. However, if users have opted out of all communication with the site, or deleted/deactivated their account, then they will not be contacted, nor will their personal information be used in this new manner. In addition, if we make any material changes in our privacy practices that do not affect user information already stored in our database, we will post a prominent notice on our websites notifying users of the change. In some cases when we post a notice, users who have opted to receive communications from us may receive a notice alerting users to such changes.

**Privacy Statement for Data Subjects Whose Personal Data May Be Collected in the European Union**

IX. EU GENERAL DATA PROTECTION REGULATION (“GDPR”)

The ASSOCIATION has global recognition and because of this may individuals within the European Economic Area (“EEA”) may contact the ASSOCIATION or visit its website and provide personal information. In order to serve these individuals, the ASSOCIATION may transfer personal information from such individuals located within the EEA (“Data Subjects”). Personal information that may be collected by us from a Data Subject in the EEA may include:

  * name
  * mailing addresses
  * telephone numbers
  * email addresses
  * payment information

Because of its global recognition, the ASSOCIATION must potentially deal with local supervisory authorities in all EU states where it has a business relationship with a Data Subject. Additionally, information that the ASSOCIATION collects may be transferred outside of the EEA, including to countries such as the United States, which have not been deemed as having “adequate” security measures by the European Commission. In these cases, your personal information will be transferred only after obtaining your consent.

X. LAWFUL GROUNDS TO PROCESS AND OBTAIN CONSENT 

Data Subjects whose personal information is collected in the EEA may withdraw consent at any time where consent is the lawful basis for processing their information. Should a Data Subject withdraw consent for processing or otherwise object to processing that impedes The ASSOCIATION’s ability to comply with applicable regulations that Data Subject may be unable to enjoy the services in which the ASSOCIATION provides.

XI. DATA SUBJECTS’ RIGHTS  

Data Subjects in the EEA whose personal information is held by the ASSOCIATION have the right to:

  * ask what information the ASSOCIATION holds about them and why;
  * ask for a copy of such information or access to such information;
  * be informed how to correct or keep that information up to date; and
  * be informed on how the ASSOCIATION is meeting its data protection obligations.

Furthermore, for data collected in the EEA, Data Subjects have the right to:

  * request a copy of such information to be sent to a third party;
  * request that data to be erased if possible and required under the GDPR;
  * request that processing of personal information be restricted if possible and required under GDPR;
  * object to processing of personal information if possible and required under GDPR;
  * object to automated decision-making where applicable; and
  * contact a supervisory authority in the EEA to lodge a complaint regarding the ASSOCIATION’s processing of your personal information.

When handling a data access or correction request, we check the identity of the requesting party to ensure that he or she is the person legally entitled to make such request. Such requests are provided free of charge however a reasonable fee may be applied charged to cover our administrative costs incurred for requests that are manifestly unfounded, excessive or repetitive.

XII. AUTOMATED DECISION-MAKING  

The ASSOCIATION does not engage in automated decision-making activities.

XIII. NON-DISCLOSURE OF INFORMATION

The ASSOCIATION does not share any personal information with any nonaffiliated third parties, except in the following circumstances:

  * information with any nonaffiliated third parties, except in the following circumstances:
  * as necessary to provide the service that the customer has requested or authorized, or to maintain and service the customer’s account;
  * as required by regulatory authorities or law enforcement officials who have jurisdiction over the ASSOCIATION and its affiliates or as otherwise required by any applicable law; and
  * to the extent reasonably necessary to prevent fraud and unauthorized transactions.

Employees of the ASSOCIATION are prohibited, either during or after termination of their employment, from disclosing personal information to any person or entity outside of the ASSOCIATION, including family members, except under the circumstances described above. An employee is permitted to disclose personal information only to such other employees who need to have access to such information to deliver our services to the customer. 

XIV. CONTACT INFORMATION FOR PERSONS LOCATED WITHIN THE EEA

If you are located in the European Economic Area (“EEA”) or Switzerland and have questions or concerns regarding the processing of your personal information, you may email us at [information@laphil.org](mailto:information@laphil.org) with “Privacy” included in the subject line or write to us at:

Attn: Privacy Office  
The Los Angeles Philharmonic Association  
151 S. Grand Avenue  
Los Angeles, CA 90012  
USA

If, as an EEA citizen, you believe that the ASSOCIATION has not adequately resolved any such issues, you have the right to contact the EU supervisory authority.

**_Last updated: June 2018_**
